## **ELIAS MEDINA**

LA PLATA · BUENOS AIRES, ARGENTINA · +54 221-5258-394 · ELIASMEDINA86@GMAIL.COM

I'm a Quality Assurance professional with 9+ years of experience in the field. I been involved in all kind of testing projects with some of the biggest names in the industry such as Electronic Arts, Tribune, Bioware and Deloitte among others.

I have work experience in the fields of Game Testing, Mobile Testing, Web Testing and Automated Testing. I'm always up for a challenge, the more technical the better. I have a broad technical set of skills that helps me a great deal to face complex tasks, and even gives me the opportunity to create tools and solutions that would help junior testers to perform their tasks in better ways.

I do love to share what I learn and had been coaching junior QC and QA analyst for years to help them grow in their careers. I'm currently working as a Senior QC Lead for complex tax projects for Globant and Deloitte companies.

## **EXPERIENCE**

SR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + DELOITTE

I'm working as a QC and QA lead analyst. Providing quality assurance and quality control processes for key projects and new web applications under active development. I'm also leading an automation initiative using WebdriverIO with JS and Node to automate core features of the applications under development. This lets me mix my technical skills with my task-force leading skills to face a highly demanding work load.

August 2016 - Present

SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + TRIBUNE PUBLISHING (NOW TRONC)

Worked on MDM implementation, a data management project in which we needed to sanitize all Tribune customer data from duplicates and outdated records while providing Tribune enterprise systems with a new data management framework. This was a very tough project and required a lot of research and presented very complex technical challenges.

December 2014 - August 2016

### SSR OC LEAD

GLOBANT + TRIBUNE PUBLISHING (NOW TRONC)

I Worked as QC Lead with Tribune Company's development team located in Los Angeles and Chicago. Where I planned, performed and monitored, QA and QC tasks and processes over several systems which were all consumed from a single mobile app. I've also performed automated testing on the mobile app and helped debugging and improving the framework.

March 2014 - December 2014

#### SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + SCHELL GAMES + AMPLIFY

I worked on an educative project for Schell Games and Amplify. This time taking care of the Quality processes performed on iOS devices as well as providing UI/UX feedback, aiming to create a really good usage experience of the products being developed while assuring the overall quality and functionality of the specified requirements.

August 2013 - February 2014

#### SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I worked as QC Lead on the release of one of the biggest multiplatform football games on the market, FIFA 14 project. My role in this project was to take care of the QA/QC validations for the Kinect & Move technologies as well as the overall stability of the title on all supported platforms. Another huge project with very serious deadlines to work with.

March 2013 - August 2013

#### OC LEAD ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I worked with EA again, this time with Montreal, Vancouver and Redwood Shores offices. I was tasked with testing and improving EA Origin client for Mac. I had a small test team of 10 employees and we verified and validated a huge software catalog to ensure they work well with Origin for Mac. (More than 200+ Titles between games and other software).

October 2012 - March 2013

#### QC LEAD ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS CANADA

I took the role of test lead of the Globant QA Test Team, this time working for EA Los Angeles, performing QA processes for the EA multiplatform title: Medal Of Honor Warfighter.

March 2012 - October 2012

#### OC ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I started working as a game tester for EA's FIFA franchise. Later I was assigned as POC (point of contact) of everything online related about the FIFA franchise and had to work closely with EA's Leads to coordinate testing efforts and communicate quality reports.

March 2011 - April 2012

#### **QA ANALYST**

MOZILLA AURORA NETWORK

I took part of a collaborative testing initiative for Mozilla's FireFox browser. My tasks involved testing the new builds released on the Mozilla Aurora Channel under different

versions of Operative Systems to ensure new versions will continue to work correctly on the OSs. Bug Reporting, analysis and testing of new requirements were also part of the job.

February 2010 - August 2010

# **EDUCATION**

### E-LEARNING PLATFORMS TO STAY IT RELEVANT!

QUALITY ASSURANCE AND PROGRAMMING

Proud student of world top's e-learning sites

Udemy, Udacity, Team Tree House, Acamica, Pluralsight, Microsoft Academy

Present

#### NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF LA PLATA

COMPUTER SCIENCE DEGREE

Computer Science Track

2003 - 2008

### TECHNICAL EDUCATION SCHOOL N°1 EET

BACHELOR DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & PROGRAMMING

August 2002 - May 2006

# **SKILLS**

QUALITY ASSURANCE, PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- Test Tracking Tools (Jira, TFS, Bugzilla)
- Functional Testing
- Regression Testing

- Cross Browser Testing & Debugging
- Compatibility Testing
- Automated Web Testing
- Agile Development & Scrum methodology
- Quality Assurance and Quality Control coaching
- Test Planning & Risk Assessment
- JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS
- NodeJS and NPM
- WordPress, React
- Selenium, Webdriver, WebdriverlO

#### **RECOMMENDATIONS**

**Mehrnaz Sadolahy**Software Engineering Manager| CSM | Leadership | Process Improvement

"I hired Elias as a QA engineer to work on a project with us for a short period of time. He did such great job that we continued assigning him to multiple projects for 2 years. Elias is very dedicated, extremely thorough with writing test cases and executing various tests. What I was particularly impressed by was his analytical skills and his ability to create effective test reports. On top of that, he is a real team player and one you can always count on. Elias would be an asset to any team."

**Rey Castillo** CSM®

Software and Systems Quality Assurance Project Lead | Project Management

"Elias and I worked together on multiple software product development projects in the testing and quality assurance capacity. He is a consummate professional with a rare talent of learning complex topics quickly, applying savvy analytical skills to help expand the scope of understanding of several key elements and significantly contributing to the quality of projects and other deliverables. Elias provided valuable leadership for our quality team as a mentor to novice members. He was a vital member in the successful deployment of various mission-critical projects who consistently exceeded high expectations and generated salient concerns in order to drive quality towards overall customer satisfaction. It was a tremendous privilege to have worked with Elias. He would be a valuable asset to any organization."

**Ana Marcolini**Project Manager | Scrum Master

"Elias es una persona sumamente responsable, con una dedicación admirable. Siempre encuentra la forma de superarse y afrontar nuevos desafíos con una visión holística que le permite lograr el éxito en todo aquello que emprenda. Una persona que realmente marca la diferencia y un rumbo para quienes trabajan a su lado."

**Damian Copello**Sr QA Analyst at Globant

"Elias is a very well-rounded tester who helped me a lot during my time in Globant. He is a quick learner and very passionate about what he does. Working with him was a smooth experience and I even got to learn a few SQL tricks from him in the process."

**Agustin Mattioli**Network and Security Engineer

"Elias has an energy and operational capability worthy of being highlighted. He's dedicated, smart and a great human being. I fully recommend him to the required position."

**Kevin David Martinez**Cyber Defense | Information Security

"Elias is a manager with a great eye for detail. His instructions are always clear and precise, leaving no room for confusion. He applies the right amount of pressure, keeping you motivated without restricting the freedom you need to work comfortably and efficiently. He can organize a group to solve problems and get the job done quickly. Quite possibly the best leader I've ever had. Highly recommendable for any position involving managing groups."

#### **Federico Laos**

QA Lead at Globant

"In my experience with Elias he proved to be one of the best QA Analyst that I've ever teamed with, and I truly hope to get to work with him again in the future. I worked with him from his day one at Globant as Tester, he showed true potential from the start. On my first project with him he was the MVP of the team, he has a keen eye for detail, and technical knowledge that allow him to find defects both ensuring proper handling or edge/stress cases, as well a polished look and feel. After moving to a new project, I handpicked Elias to work for EA Canada and Bioware, in 'QA Analyst' role with new tasks and responsibilities. He excelled again, not only as tester/bug finder, but as an analyst, getting involved in test planning and proving valuable and constructive feedback to the client and his management. He is very dedicated to his work, committed to his team and project, always looking to improve. He's relentless, will ask for answer (or help) until he gets it."